CURRICULUM VITAE

I am passionate about learning and growing as a web developer, every new project allows me to gain the skills required to deliver exceptional work which is then expressed in the next project.

My work experiences so far are similar in that they focus on helping clients achieve the outcome they desire with great attention to detail, whether that is through great customer service, education as an English teacher, as a support worker, or now as a Web Developer. I enjoy learning new languages and to me, coding is just another language that allows me to express myself through visual means.

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: Darren Evans

RESIDES: Herne Bay, Kent

TRANSPORT: Full UK driving licence and own vehicle

CONTACT DETAILS: (M) 07921 512050

(E) djevy@live.co.uk

(W) https://darrenrevans.co.uk/ (GH) https://github.com/djevy

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE:

I have most recently worked as a Full-stack Web Developer for Reach plc as part of the data unit. In this position I created interactive widgets utilising an array different data. These widgets can then be placed on articles of well-known and popular online newspapers such as the Daily Mail or the Mirror. This position has been mainly independent and has allowed me to improve my problem-solving skills swiftly. I loved the role and look forward to applying the knowledge I have learnt to other projects.

In my first position as a Junior Front End Developer, I was building a learning management system for a six-month fixed term contract, learning at an efficient and rapid pace to fulfil the requirements of each sprint's goals. This position gave me the chance to put my React skills into practice and gave me a desire to work with this library again in the future.

In this role I was able to express the skills that I learned in my training, as well as develop lots of new skills and best practice techniques.

I graduated from a coding Traineeship as a Full-stack Developer in April of 2021. The training included completing 2 real-world projects successfully to specification using a wide range of programming languages.

CAREER HISTORY:

Dec 2021 – Feb 2023 POSITION HELD:

Reach

Web Developer

- Worked on the development of highly reusable widgets for online articles for the likes of the Mirror, Daily Mail, Express, and many more.
- Translated designs and data into interactive widgets that convey data to the reader as to support the article it appears in.
- Worked with editors in the data unit to create interactive widgets that present data in an interesting way.
- Gained and improved my skills by creating:
 - O Widgets using jQuery, AJAX, SQL and PHP.
 - Widget generators for the editors to create their own widgets using a template and their own data.
 - Widgets utilising the leaflet.js library among many others.

June 2021 – Dec 2021 POSITION HELD:

ZUSTECH LIMITED

Junior Web Developer

- Worked on the development of a Learning Management System.
- Translated designs and wireframes into a highly responsive user interface and reusable components using React.js.
- Used JIRA as a task tracking system to maintain the history of bugs/issues on an everyday basis.
- Created custom React Components, as well as worked with library Components to implement Backend-APIs.
- Worked on features such as:
 - Site wide language changing
 - Secure login
 - Payment handling
 - o Application submission

Apr 2020 - June 2021

Career break

 I invested time in studying and obtaining my Microsoft certification and completing projects to gain practical experience with the coding languages that I have studied.

CODING TRAINEESHIP:

IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship – Full stack developer 1-year program

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- PHP, jQuery, SQL, Bootstrap
- Java, Python, React, C#
- Git, API

I have gained my Microsoft 98-383: Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS certificate. More information on this certification can be found at: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/exams/98-383

Below are the two briefs of development projects I successfully completed with IT Career Switch which can be found in my bio: https://darrenrevans.co.uk/

Portfolio Project #1: "Gazetteer"

 The specification was to reply to a website specification for a map-based app to provide information on countries — with a focus on a "mobile first" development. Preferably using a framework, to then develop HTML, CSS and JavaScript with JQuery modules that use PHP server-based components to source data from third party APIs (Geonames, OpenWeather). The solution is assessed on its delivery to specification, functionality, and usability.

Portfolio Project #2: "Company Directory"

 A more rigorous reply to this specification was required as a user requirements document was needed to be prepared which, when signed off, triggers the release of SQL allowing to develop a "mobile-first" application to maintain a company personnel database (MySQL). Sign off is only achieved upon the student supplying an independently witnessed document providing confirmation of the system's ability to perform error free. Dec 2020 – Jan 2021 POSITION HELD:

OFP Timber Frames Machine Operative

- Operated dangerous wood cutting machinery
- Sorted timber frame products through manual labour

Sep 2020 – Nov 2020 POSITION HELD:

Optima Care Support Worker

- Provided care in an assisted living home
- Ensured that the client could live a healthy and happy life

Mar 2019 – Feb 2020 POSITION HELD:

Interac, Japan Assistant English Teacher

- Taught as the primary English language teacher, and also provided lesson assistance at times
- Managed classes of up to 40 students at a Junior High School, with 800 students in total
- Provided English language knowledge, marking, and proofreading

Nov 2018 – Jan 2019 POSITION HELD:

Tesco

Customer Assistant

- Worked to ensure customer satisfaction
- Provided stock replenishment for the shop floor
- Worked in multiple departments as required

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018 POSITION HELD:

Global Fire and Security Assistant Engineer

- Carried out fire maintenance services and assisted with installation of fire alarms and other devices
- Developed teamwork, communication, punctuality and independence skills
- Talked to important clients and worked in busy and sometimes unfamiliar environments

Nov 2017 – Jun 2018 POSITION HELD:

Tesco

Customer Assistant

- Ensured that the customer experience was the best it could be, by communicating effectively with customers and being helpful
- Handled money accurately to guarantee that no mistakes were made
- Multitasking replenished stock remaining mindful of any customers that needed assistance

Feb 2017 – Aug 2017 POSITION HELD:

DEOW Language School English Teacher

- Taught people of all ages, from 10 to 80 years old, English as a foreign language
- Constantly controlled the classroom and maintained the attention of up to 10 people at a time

- Gained practical work experience, and management and problem-solving skills
- Gained a strong sense of confidence in controlling a situation

Jul 2015 – Nov 2015 POSITION HELD: McDonald's Crew Member

- Teamwork and communication
- Dedicated, organised and punctual
- Health and safety, cleanliness and hygiene

Jun 2014 - Sep 2014 POSITION HELD:

Global Fire and Security Assistant Engineer

EDUCATION:

2020 Codecademy

Web Development Career Path

2019 TEFL

Certificate in Teaching English as a Foreign Language

2014 – 2018 University of Sheffield

BA East Asian Studies (Grade: 2:2)

2016 – 2017 Sophie University, Tokyo

Japanese Language Programme

2007 – 2014 The Westlands School

Three A-Levels (*Grade:* $A^* - B$) Nine GCSEs (*Grade:* B - C)